《开心汉堡店》第五季第五集
用喷的  别用说的
除虫害公司
翻译：小布拿拿     斯人
我  伟大的查克・查尔斯
I want to give a big Chuck Charles
翻译&校对&总监：Iz
感谢渺小的各位前来参加
thanks to all you little people for coming down
今年的"狼吞虎咽"美食节
to this year's Wharf It Down Food Festival,
这美食节多年来都是
which, for so many years, has been a strange,
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
半诡异半凄凉的活动
slightly sad event, where artisans
只有商贩们卖力叫卖小吃  但是
try to sell specialty foods. But...
第一届年度最佳汉堡比赛
今年则不同  因为有我查克・查尔斯
not this year, thanks to me, Chuck Charles,
和第一届年度最佳汉堡比赛
and our 1st Annual Best Burger Contest!
现在  我们来见见参赛者
Now, we've met our contestants,
我们已经事先解释过
we've explained the rules
这次透明公正又简单的大赛规则了
of this really, truly, simple event.
只差一件事
But the only thing we haven't done
就是开启倒计时
is start the clock.
比赛开始
Here we go...
好咧  鲍勃
All right, Bob.
加油  我们必胜
Let's do it, let's win!
必胜  必胜  必胜
Win! Win! Win!
-琳  拜托  -开始吧
- Lin, please. -Let's go!
咱低调一点行吗
Take it down a notch, okay?
-低调点  -孩子们  来呀
- Or five? - Kids, come on,
为你们老爸助威
cheer for your father.
加油  加油  加油
Cheer! Cheer! Cheer!
-琳  别喊了  -加油
- Lin, stop. - Cheer.
老爸  咧嘴一笑  活力闪耀
Dad, big smile, big energy!
这就对了  宝贝
That's it, doll.
伙计  你这么快就汗流浃背了怎么办
Hey, you're sweating too much already, buddy.
控制节奏
Pace yourself.
冲啊  老爸  老妈
Go, Mom and Dad!
我是说  好好做汉堡
I mean, stay there and cook,
不是真的让你们往哪儿冲
don't go anywhere.
抱歉把你们搞糊涂了
Sorry if I'm being confusing.
好了  来  开始吧  快  快  快
Okay, come on. Go! Cook! Cook! Cook! Cook!
我们来采访下参赛者
Let's check in with our contestants.
斯基普・马瑞琪
Skip Marooch!
我念对了吗
Am I saying that right?
是的  斯基普
Yes, Skip.
很好  你来自巴基斯坦
Great! So, you're from Pakistan,
经营着一家很成功的餐馆
you've got a successful restaurant,
现在还在各地宣传新书  有你不会的吗
you're on a book tour. Guy, what can't you do?
我不会抱怨  因为万事都太顺利了
Complain... everything is going so well.
你这家伙
This guy.
你今天打算做什么
So, what are you making today?
我已经爱上你了
I already love you.
今天  我要用我奶奶的特制调料
Well, today, I will be making a pomegranate
做一道石榴红辣椒
and green chili chutney burger
加青辣椒混合酸辣酱汉堡
with my grandmother's special spice blend.
就两个字  好吃  好吃
Two words: yum and yum.
她总是对我说  "全都要加调料"
She always told me, "Put spice on everything."
她还有一句名言是  "我恨周一"
She also said, "I hate Mondays,"
但一直没人承认这话是她发明的
but she never got credit for that.
我真想见见她
I would love to meet her.
太晚了
Ah, too late.
我知道我们是为鲍勃加油来的
Sheesh. I know we're here for Bob,
但要讨厌那人可真不容易
but it's hard to root against that guy.
他确实招人喜欢
He is likeable.
闭嘴  我听不到他们做饭了
Shush! I can't hear them cooking.
斯基普・马瑞琪
Skip Marooch...
真不敢相信我们能和他同台竞技
I can't believe we're competing against that guy.
他都出书了  我还读过
He has a book; I read it.
我是说  算是读过吧
I mean, I mostly read it.
我把所有图片都翻了
I looked at all the pictures.
我到底为什么想要来参加这个呢
Why did I think this was a good idea?
三周前
告诉你  我准备报名了
You know what? I'm signing up.
我们要参赛啦
We're doing it!
就这么干吧  去吧
Do it! We're doing it!
感觉好极了
This feels good!
去干吧
Do it!
安静点
Quiet!
我不确定你们说的"干"
I don't know what kind of "Doing it"
是指什么
you're talking about,
但你们吵死了
but you're too loud!
抱歉
Sorry...
我真痛恨比赛
I really hate contests.
所以我们才制定了
This is why we made a
"酒后勿做决定"的规则
"No signing up for things while drunk" rule.
什么  那样的话吉恩就不会去学芭蕾了
Wha...? Gene never would've taken ballet.
看看人家斯基普
Look at Skip over there.
我觉得我们不可能赢
I-I don't think we can win this.
我就是洛奇  他是阿波罗.奎迪
It's-it's like I'm Rocky and he's Apollo Creed.
以拳击为主题的系列电影《洛基》中的角色
史泰龙主演
很好呀  最后都是洛奇赢嘛
That's good! Rocky always won.
洛基在第一部里输了  琳
Rocky lost in the first movie, Lin.
可他爬了那么多楼梯啊
But he walked up all those stairs.
真不公平
That's not fair.
我们来听
And... let's get a few words
懒汉鲍勃・贝尔彻说几句  你好
with Bob "The Slob" Belcher.Hi.
我不是懒汉
That's not my nickname.
现在是了  大家都听到了
Well, it is now, everyone heard it.
朋友  我和鲍勃有一些恩怨
Bob and I have a bit of a history, folks.
我曾好心让他
I graciously allowed him
上我的早间访谈节目
onto my morning talk show,
结果是  他害我被炒了
and in turn, he got me fired!
不是我
I didn't get you fired.
-是琳达  - 你好  查克
- Linda did. - Hi, Chuck.
你们打算做什么破汉堡  鲍勃
So, what stupid burger are you making, Bob?
我的汉堡才不破  它好得很
Okay, well, it's not stupid; It's smart.
我叫它"黑蒜撑场子汉堡"
I call it the Bet It All on Black Garlic Burger.
-是用...  -烂名字
- It's made with... - Stupid name.
-什么  -烂名字
- What? - Stupid name.
它才不...  我去
It's not... Oh, my God.
是用黑蒜做的
I-It's made with black garlic.
这是一种发酵过的蒜
It's a fermented garlic;
来自韩国
It comes from Korea.
可别把责任推给韩国  鲍勃
Don't blame Korea for your stupid burger, Bob.
对韩国对汉堡都不公平
Not fair to them or burgers.
斯基普  石榴红辣椒加青辣椒混合酸辣酱汉堡
我没有怪他们
I-I'm not blaming them...
烂黑蒜汉堡
The Stupid Black Garlic Burger.
-屏幕打上去  -我去
- Put it up on the screen. - Oh, my God.
鲍勃  烂黑蒜汉堡
我们做到了
We made it up.
看  我们上屏幕了
Look, we're on the screen.
-查克恨我们  -不会吧
- Chuck hates us. - No...
没事  我也恨他
It's okay, I hate him, too.
天哪  这真是个坏主意
God, this was a bad idea.
不会  这很好玩  很好玩
No... It's fun. It's fun...
这边是渴望成为
Over here, we have the Prince of Pizza
"芝士汉堡宰相"的"比萨小王子"
trying to become the Chancellor of Cheeseburgers...
吉米・派丝多
Jimmy Pesto.
谢谢  查克
Thank you, Chuck.
吉米・派丝多披萨饼店以其
Jimmy Pesto's is known
老少咸宜的友好氛围闻名
for our family-friendly atmosphere,
我们提供节日特价饮料
festive drink specials
以及意大利风味食品
and Italian-flavored foods.
好了
All right...
等我今天赢得比赛之后
A-A-And after I win this contest today,
我们又会以牛至汉堡而闻名
we're also gonna be known for our oregano Burger!
好吧
All... right!
那里面是什么
And what's in that?
一大堆牛至[一种草药]
Just a ton of oregano.
吉米・派丝多  牛至汉堡
很多牛至哦[又指女性高潮]
The Big O!
-别那样说  -什么
- Don't say "Big O." - What...?
好吧  我啥也不说了
A... all right, I won't say anything, then, ever.
听起来好可怕
Sounds horrible.
看来就是我和斯基普一决雌雄了
I guess it's just us and Skip here.
好吧
All right,
该让黑蒜出场了
time to break out the black garlic.
-琳  -这就来
- Lin? - You got it!
-不在这里  -等等  什么
- It's not in here. - Wait. What?
不在冰盒里  空的
Not in the cooler. It's empty.
完蛋了  完蛋了
Oh, crap. Oh, crap.
完蛋了  完蛋了  完蛋了  完蛋了
Oh, crap. Oh, crap, crap, crap. Crap!
三十分钟前
吉恩  你能去厨房把黑蒜拿来吗
Gene, can you go to the kitchen and grab the black garlic?
好咧
On it!
啥颜色的
What color is it?
黑色  吉恩
It's black, Gene.
等等  你说啥是黑色的
Wait. What's black?
黑蒜  就在柜子上面
The garlic. On the counter.
我现在去的那个厨房里的柜子吗
In the kitchen? Where I am?
-你确定你在厨房吗  -应该是吧
- Are you?! - I think so.
是的  在柜子上面
Well, then, yes, on the counter.
好的  我感觉很好  老爸
Okay. I feel really good about this, Dad.
-我感觉超棒  -干得好  各位
- I feel great about it. - Way to go, everybody.
吉恩
Gene!
老爸  我们这是在干嘛
Dad?! What are we doing?
我分明让吉恩到厨房去拿黑蒜了
I asked Gene to get the black garlic from the kitchen...
那是我做这汉堡唯一最重要的食材
the single most important ingredient in my recipe...
而现在冰盒里却空空如也
and we're looking at an empty cooler!
好了  别抓狂
Okay, don't freak out.
大家好
Hi. Hi, everyone.
你们好
Hi. Hi. Hello.
我没有抓狂
I'm not freaking out!
他没事  只是有点犯傻气
He's fine. He's... he's silly.
加点别的就好了嘛
Just put something else on the burger.
这个怎么样
What about a...
燕麦卷汉堡
Oh, a-a granola bar burger!
二分之一燕麦卷汉堡
Half a granola bar burger.
好啊  好啊  我们就做这个
Yeah, yeah, let-let's do that.
真是个很棒的主意
That's a great idea.
太好了  我先把它切块
Great! I'll start chopping it up.
放的时间太长了
Oh, it's old.
没关系  没事
Oh, that's okay. That's fine.
-我们可以的  -天哪  琳达
- We can make it. - Linda. Oh, my God,
我是在说反话
I wasn't serious.
看看屏幕
Look at the screen.
上面写的是"烂黑蒜汉堡"
It says "Stupid Black Garlic Burger".
我很确定  我们的黑蒜汉堡要是没黑蒜
I'm pretty sure we can't beat Skip Marooch
是无论如何也赢不了斯基普的
if we don't have black garlic on our black garlic burger!
够了  天哪
Okay! Geez.
孩子们  孩子们  快来
Kids! Kids, come here!
我的回答是"是的  你看起来吓傻了"
The answer is yes, you look terrified.
-你是想问这个吗  -听着
- Is that the question? - Listen!
吉恩  你对我的黑蒜做了什么
Gene, what did you do with the black garlic?
冰盒里为什么没有
It's not in the cooler!
淡定点  老爸  黑蒜是啥
Calm down, Dad. What is black garlic?
我要你们现在
I need you guys to go back to the restaurant,
用最快的速度回餐厅
get the black garlic and bring it back here
把黑蒜找到送过来
as fast as you possibly can!
没问题  不说我也正打算回家的
No problem. It's on my way, anyway, bro.
别别  蒂娜  露易丝  和他一起去
No, no! Tina, Louise, go with your brother.
快点  时间紧迫
And hurry! The clock is ticking.
我们可以讨论下这时间有多紧迫
Let's talk more about this clock that's ticking.
滴答  滴答  滴答
Tick, tick, tick.
你想怎样  露易丝  露易丝
What do want, Louise? Louise?!
今后再不让我们在餐馆帮忙
We never have to work again.
我可以让你们明天休息一天
You can have the day off tomorrow.
-成交  -好的  接着
- Deal! - Great. Here.
不要扔东西嘛
Don't throw things!
我们可从来不扔东西
We don't throw things!
也从来接不到
We don't catch them, either.
我们又不是马戏团  老爸
We're not in the circus, Dad. Yeah!
赶紧去吧
Just go!
嗨  贝尔彻小孩
Hey, Belcher boppers!
米基  等等  你蹬三轮啊
Mickey! Wait, you drive a pedi-cab?
你不是在奇幻码头工作吗
I thought you worked at Wonder Wharf.
我开始在
Oh, I just started driving this
节假日蹬三轮了
during festivals and weekends.
靠拉那些懒货和醉鬼大赚一笔
Make a lot of money hauling around lazies and drunks.
我们两者都是  带我们一程吧
We are both. Give us a ride!
你们这些小孩
Hey, you kids don't want a ride
不会要坐那牙签腿的车吧
from toothpick legs over here.
看看我这一腿的三轮肌
Check out these pedal monsters, huh?
像是一堆蛇在皮椅里窜来窜去
It looks like a bunch of snakes inside a leather armchair.
-是的  -让开  曼宁  这是我的活
- Yup. - Back off, Manny. This is my fare.
是吗  可这是我的地盘  菜鸟  来啊
Oh, yeah? Well this is my turf, rookie. Here.
我的第一次地盘之争
Hey! My first turf war!
我看我们还是传统点用走的吧
Okay, well, I-I think we'll go old-school pedestrian.
-再见各位  -地盘战好运
- See you guys! - Good luck with your turf war.
多谢
Thanks!
鲍勃  你看起来汗津津的
So, Bob, you look sweaty.
你觉得自己有把握赢吗
Think you have what it takes to beat the competition?
我觉得没有
I personally doubt it.
我没有出汗
I'm not sweating.
好吧  我出了
Oh, I am. Okay.
我  我还在准备
I, uh, I was just prepping.
正常  一切正常
Normal, everything's fine.
我们的食材都齐了  查克  一个不少
We've got all our ingredients, Chuck. All of 'em.
不问自答  无聊到家
Unnecessary information, totally boring.
我还是过来和斯基普聊聊
I'm gonna go ahead and talk to Skip.
-你好  -这小子在这呢
- Hello! - There he is, guy!
再和我们聊聊你祖母的秘制辣酱
Tell us more about your grandmother's secret spice blend.
好吧  里面加了藏红花
All right, well, there is saffron in it.
不好  我说漏嘴了
Oh, no, I told you the secret!
现在只有杀你灭口了
I have to kill you now!
死吧  死吧  死吧
Die, die, die!
热情  迷人
Warm, charming,
幽默  手劲还很大
and funny, strong hands, to boot!
这就是为什么他能出书而鲍勃不行的原因
That's why he's got a book and Bob doesn't.
在这呢  恶臭小公主
There you are, my stinky princess!
我们来接你了  跟咱走吧
We're getting you out of here! Come with us!
我的"老头乐"锅铲在那儿呢
Hey, there's my back-scratching spatula!
你怎么在厨房啊
What are you doing in the kitchen?
吉恩  你要把它挤碎了
Gene, you're crushing it!
什么  不  我的T恤
What? Oh, no! My shirt!
老爸这下非输不可了
You just cost Dad the competition!
谁管老爸  我们的休假泡汤了才是真的
Forget Dad. You just cost us our day off!
也许还能用
Maybe it's still good!
我用我的"老头乐"把它刮下来
I'll scrape it off with my back scratcher.
原来前胸挠起来也很爽
It works on your front, too.
你是哪一部分听不懂
What's so hard to understand about,
黑蒜我找到了
I saw the black garlic,
接着我又看见了我的"老头乐"锅铲
But then I saw my spatula back scratcher,
我伸手去拿它的时候
And when I reached for it,
你的黑蒜就全糊我肚子上了
your black garlic got smeared all over my belly?
天哪  吉恩  让蒂娜接电话
Oh, my God. Gene, put Tina on the phone.
字面意思  把蒂娜放电话上
她块头太大
She's pretty big.
把电话放蒂娜上比较容易
It'd be easier to put the phone on Tina.
吉恩
Gene!
我是蒂娜
This is Tina.
蒂娜  听好了  去你妈的内衣抽屉
Tina, listen to me. Go to your mom's bra drawer
找到她的私房钱
and find the cash she thinks is secret.
那里没钱  又没钱
There's no money in there! There's no money.
拿20美元去第三大道的那家特色食品店
Take $20 and go to that specialty food market on Third.
叫"无花果酱"的
Fig Jam.
就不能去其他地方买吗
Aren't there any other places we could go?
那是镇上唯一卖黑蒜的店
It's the only place in town that has black garlic.
快点  只剩12分钟了
Hurry. We're down to 12 minutes here.
老爸挂了
Dad hung up on me,
没关系  我知道他爱我的
but it's okay because I know he loves me,
他说我们得去无花果酱店
and he says we have to go to Fig Jam.
-无花果酱店  -无花果酱店
- Fig Jam? - Fig Jam.
上周
我们要这条
We'll take this dark chocolate bar
含培根和红辣椒的黑巧克力
with bacon and red pepper flakes, please.
好的  13块
Okay, that'll be $13.
什么
What?!
不  我们就买一个
No, we're just getting one,
这些应该够了  给你
so this should cover it. Here you go.
我觉得你们来错商店了
You know, I think you three may be in the wrong store.
加油站那的泡泡糖球机
Perhaps you'd be more comfortable shopping
应该更适合你们
at the gum ball machine at the gas station.
你在赶我们走吗
Are you kicking us out?
不  我只是建议
No. I am strongly suggesting
你们带着这点可怜的钱
that you take your business elsewhere,
去别的地方购物
what little of it you have.
好呀
All right.
总有一天我会傍到大款改头换面
But when a rich john sets me up in style,
到时候我会回来的
I'm coming back.
此处吉恩将自己比作电影《风月俏佳人》中的女主
你就等着看别人销售业绩疯涨吧
And you better hope you don't work on commission.
这巧克力你从哪儿进的货  你屁股吗
Yeah, where'd you import this chocolate from anyway, your butt?
-不  -这海盐焦糖薯片
- No. - Yeah, and where'd you import
你从哪儿进的货  你屁股吗
these sea salt caramel crisps from, your butt?
啊  是比利时
Oh, Belgium.
够了  以后禁止你们来这儿
That's it. You're banned.
我们才要禁止你  快滚出去
We ban you. Get out of the store!
-这是我的店  -滚出去
- I will not get out of my store! - You... get out!
-你不准进  -你不准
- You are banned! - You're banned!
-你不准  -你不准  -你不准
- You're banned! - You're banned! - You're banned!
-你不准  -你不准
- You are banned! - You're banned!
我们得试一下  各位
We have to try, guys.
要是没有黑蒜的话
If we don't get this black garlic,
老爸就要输了  那会给我们家抹黑的
dad is going to lose, and our family will be dishonored.
也是  我们家名声本来就不好
It's not like we've got a whole bunch of honor to spare, is it?
-是啊  -走吧
- No. - No. - Let's go!
斯基普・马瑞琪做的东西很特别
Oh, wow, Skip Marooch is cooking up something special.
闻着很香  他做起菜来超帅的
It smells good, and he looks good doing it.
这句重来  他看着精神不错
Scratch that. He looks great.
-谢啦  -接下来
- Thank you! - Moving on.
我们看看吉米・派丝多做的怎么样
Let's see how Jimmy Pesto's doing.
-大功告成  -什么
- Done! Ding! - Ooh, what?
吉米还剩十分钟的时候就摆盘完成了
Jimmy has plated his burgers with ten minutes left.
不过  等评委品尝时
Course, those burgers may get cold
这汉堡就该冷了
before the judges have a chance to...
原来他们带了个加热灯
Oh, okay, brought a little heat lamp with him.
加热灯能让食物更有味
Yeah. Heat lamp adds a little flavor.
还能给我的蜥蜴暖身
And it keeps my lizard warm!
你能闭嘴吗  求你了
Would you?! Come on!
我们来看看鲍勃
Let's check in on Bob,
虽然我没兴趣
because we kind of have to.
切来切去
Lots of chopping.
他的秃顶面积越来越大  油光发亮
His bald spot's getting bigger and shinier.
估计头发都掉食物里了
Hair probably falling out all over his food.
真是个恶心的生物
What a disgusting creature.
我早在他的头发
I'm catching all the hair
掉进食物前就把它们都接住了
before it even comes close to the food.
天  真的在掉呢
God, it is coming out.
你老婆真是个幸运的女人  鲍勃
Your wife is a lucky woman, Bob.
谢谢
Thank you!
无花果酱店
-也许他不记得我们了  -禁止入内
- Maybe he won't recognize us. - Banned!
老兄  别玩这一套了
Hey, come on. Let's not do this again.
我们从头来过  你刚说你的名字是
Let's start fresh. What'd you say your name was?
我没说  也不关你的事
I didn't. It's none of your business.
别看我的名牌
Hey, don't look at my nametag.
是雷  我看到了
It's Ray. I saw it.
雷[光线]  我喜欢
Ray, I love that.
一线阳光
Ray of sunshine.
一线希望
Ray of hope.
我们需要一些黑蒜救急
We need some emergency black garlic.
是紧急黑蒜事件
It's a black garlic emergency.
紧急黑蒜事件
A black garlic emergency.
这样的话  不行
So... Well, in that case... No!
"不行"只比"行"多一个字
A "No" is just a "Yes" Upside-down.
-出去  -我们付双倍的价钱
- Get out. - We'll pay double.
-是吗  -是的
- Really? - Yes.
好吧  16美元
All right, $16.
还真是无商不奸啊
That's the ray of greed I remember.
吉恩  钱呢
Gene, where's the cash?
我们得走了  快点  我们得走了
We got to go. Come on, we got to go.
一个滑滑板的大男孩儿
A cool older kid with a skateboard
问我要了一块钱
asked me for a dollar.
于是  我给了他二十块
So, I gave him the $20
他滑去找零了
and he's skating right back with the change.
吉恩  你个白痴
Gene, you fool.
他不会回来的
He's not coming back.
永远别信滑滑板的男孩儿
Never trust a boy with a skateboard.
他们太快了
They're too fast.
雷  朋友  新提议
Hey, Ray, friend, uh, new plan:
我把吉恩押给你
I'm gonna give you Gene,
让我拿走...
and then I'll take...
立马出去  禁止入内
Out now. Banned.
禁止入内
Banned!
该实行
Time for Operation
黑蒜解救行动了
Black Garlic Down Freedom.
那是啥
What's that?
我们稍候会回来付钱的
We'll come back and pay for it later!
谢谢你的帮助  雷
Thanks for all your help, Ray!
给我回来
Get back here!
-米基  -孩子们
- Mickey! - Hey, kids!
-嗨  -嗨  罗恩
- Hey. - Hi, Ron.
挪个地儿  伙计
Hey, move over, buddy.
不好意思  小朋友们  我在做生意呢
Sorry, gang, I'm kind of in the middle of a fair here.
我要去图书馆
I was going to the library.
坐三轮去那儿是我每周一次的挥霍
Taking a pedi-cab there is my weekly splurge.
可我们偷东西了
But we stole something.
你咋不早说  去哪儿
Oh, why didn't you say so? Where to?
带我们去美食节
Take us to the food festival
全速前进
and step on it!
-停车  -留神点  冒失鬼
- Stop! - Ho, ho, ho there, cowboy.
我给你二十块
I will give you 20 bucks
帮我追上那辆三轮
if you catch up to that pedi-cab.
等等  啥
Wait, what?
你说那抢生意的面条腿小偷么
You mean that spaghetti-legged fare thief?
没错
Yes.
宝贝儿  瞧好
Oh, baby.
-米基  你要完蛋了  -好吧
- Mickey, you are going down. - Okay.
追上他们
Let's get 'em!
让我来拿黑蒜
Let me hold the black garlic.
我想为杀害它的兄弟道歉
I want to apologize for murdering its brother.
不行  吉恩  我认为这不是个好主意
No, Gene. I don't think that's a good idea.
就是  我们还想要休假一天呢
Yeah, we're trying to get a day off here.
等会儿  我为什么不能拿着黑蒜
Wait, why can't I hold the black garlic?
因为你总是
It's just that you always...
我不想说"搞砸所有的事"
I don't want to say "Screw everything up“ ,
没准露易丝愿意说
But maybe Louise does?
-你总把事情搞砸  -等等  我吗
- You screw everything up! - Wait, me?
我吉恩・贝尔彻吗
This Gene Belcher?
你总是容易分心
It's just sometimes you lose focus.
吉恩  你的名字在我们家就是个动词
Your name is a verb in this family, Gene.
叫做"吉恩出神"
We call it "Gene-ing out."
我还以为那是饱餐一顿后脱掉裤子的意思
I thought that meant taking off your shorts after a good meal.
不是  -我前几天
No. - I was Gene-ing out
上班时就"吉恩出神"了
at work the other day.
我这会儿就在"吉恩出神"
I'm Gene-ing out right now.
米基  别这样  米基  嘿
Mickey, no! Mickey, hey!
赶紧带我们去美食节  越快越好
You're taking us to the food festival as fast you can!
好好好好好
Oh, right, right, right, right, right, right, right.
天呐  我是个动词  是个贬义动词
Oh, my God. I'm a verb. I'm a bad verb.
你是个贬词
You're a berb.
我是个贬词
I'm a berb!
离比赛结束还有八分钟
Eight minutes left until burger judgment day!
孩子们现在该回来了啊  我们完蛋了
The kids should've been back by now. We're screwed.
鲍勃  你不是说你是洛奇嘛
Bob, you said you were Rocky.
快  像洛奇一样  喊声"艾黛丽安"
Come on. Start acting like Rocky. Scream "Adrian."
电影中洛奇的女友
-我  我不想喊艾黛丽安  -快喊
- I-I don't want to scream "Adrian." - Scream "Adrian"!
琳达  这比喻不管用了
Linda, that analogy doesn't work anymore.
洛奇的儿子可没把他的拳击手套落家里
Rocky's son didn't leave Rocky's boxing gloves at home.
是嘛  洛奇的儿子哈
Yeah. Rocky's son, huh?
我看呐...  算了
Well, maybe... Eh, forget it.
啥  你想说啥
No, what? Wh-What were you gonna say?
我是说  你挑了我们最不靠谱的孩子
I'm just saying, you picked our least responsible kid
做最重要的事
to do the most important thing.
也许你就想让他搞砸来着
Maybe you kind of expected him to screw up.
-太扯了  琳  -是么
- That is ridiculous, Lin. - Well...
没有黑蒜
forgetting the black garlic sort of
你就有了失败的理由
lets you off the hook for losing.
好像这不是你的错
Like it's not your fault.
突然间  你就有了一个不获胜的
All of a sudden, you got a built-in excuse
完美借口
for not being the best.
太荒谬了  这
That is crazy. That's...
好像没错  天呐
maybe right? Oh, my God.
是孩子们  "拿到了大蒜  犯了法
Oh, it's the kids! "Got garlic. Broke law.
你们回头搞定  赶来了  '笑脸'"
You fix later. On our way. 'Smiley face.'"
-笑脸耶  -天呐  他们搞定了
- Smiley face! - Oh, my God. They got it.
他们要来了  这样我们东西就全了
They're coming. We're gonna have everything we need.
-没借口了  -没有了
- No more excuses. - No.
我好怕怕啊
I'm terrified.
所以我是
So I was ri...
琳达  你是对的
Linda, you were right.
没错  我  是  对  的
Yes! Right! Me!
你不用这么说的
You don't have to say that.
是雷  他越追越紧了
It's Ray, and he's either getting bigger or closer.
曼宁载着他呢
He's got Manny driving him.
别担心  我让他慢下来
Don't worry, I'll slow him down.
那本书过期了  我干嘛那样
That was overdue. Why did I do that?
他们在向我们扔东西
They're throwing stuff at us.
别扔东西啊  老兄
No throwsies, man!
就是  别扔东西
Yeah! No throwsies.
我们一定要把这个带给老爸
We got to get this to dad.
快点  追上他  快点
Go. Go. Get him. Faster.
-快点  -我在快了
- Faster. - I am going!
我想让你们知道  我会誓死抵抗的
I just want you kids to know, I will fight.
我会打败曼宁或者雷
I will fight Manny or Ray,
不过我  我更愿意和雷交战
but I-I prefer to fight Ray, actually,
因为他比较弱
'cause he's smaller.
真好  谢谢  罗恩
Nice. Thanks, Ron.
-不客气  -到赛场了
- Ah, no problem. - There's the contest!
米基  骑快点
Mickey, pedal harder.
从这些人身上碾过去
Mow these people down!
不  小火车
Oh, no, a train!
避开  米基  避开
Beat it, Mickey! Beat it.
该死
Damn it!
不
No...!
抱歉了  孩子们
Sorry, kids.
只能载你们到这儿了
You're gonna have to run from here.
你们呆在这儿封锁入口
You guys stay here and block.
我会像屁冲出屁眼一样冲出人群
I'll cut through the crowd like a fart through butter.
让我来拿大蒜
Let me take the garlic.
我需要它
I need this.
这是我的赎罪之歌
This is my redemption song.
《赎罪之歌》为鲍勃・马利的歌曲
鲍勃・马利  赐予我力量吧
Bob Marley, give me strength!
这可是美食节  吉恩
This is a food festival, Gene.
这是你分心的雷区
It's a distraction minefield for you.
没错  吉恩  留下来  帮我堵雷
Yeah, Gene. Stay here and help me block Ray.
我们来开一场围堵派对
It'll be a block party.
好吧  快看  那朵云好像
Okay. Hey, look, that cloud looks like
一只恐龙骑在啥玩意儿上
a dinosaur on a thing.
哪儿呢
Where?
难以置信
I can't believe it!
吉恩让我们"吉恩出神"了
Gene made us Gene out!
真的诶  我看到了
Oh, yeah, I see it.
首届最佳汉堡大赛
好的  吉恩  把黑蒜送给老爸
Okay, Gene. Get this black garlic to dad.
别分心
Don't lose focus.
松饼  不  别分心
Muffins. No, don't lose focus!
嗨  我是罗恩
Hi. I'm Ron.
-我要堵住你  -那些孩子呢
- I'm blocking you. - Where are those kids?
你在说我们吗
Oh, you mean us?
-我们是你的脚踝  雷  -嗨
- Meet your new cankles, Ray. - Hi.
黑蒜在哪儿
Where's the black garlic?
你拿不回来的  已经太远了
You'll never get it. It's too far away,
再说  你已经被我们钉住了
and as we've already said, you're cankled.
放开我
Don't you cankle me!
很好
These are good.
会好的  琳达  帮我看看
These are gonna be good. Linda, be my eyes.
-看到孩子们了吗  -没看到
- You see the kids out there? - No, I don't.
他们长啥样
What do they look like?
天呐  我好恐慌  我好恐慌
Oh, God. I'm panicking. I'm panicking.
免费杯子蛋糕风味冰淇淋
Free cupcake-flavored ice cream,
配华夫饼
served on a waffle!
杀了我吧
You're killing me!
披萨玉米饼
Pizza tacos.
Pizza tacos?
一块钱十个
Ten for one dollar.
别告诉我一块钱十个
Don't you tell me "Ten for one dollar."
机器人蛋糕
Robot cake,
放过我吧
release your hold on me!
你在无花果酱店上班吗
So, uh, you work at Fig Jam, huh?
我听说你的无花果酱很棒啊
I-I-I heard you had great fig jam.
是的  很好吃
Oh, yes, it's delicious.
但你永远也吃不到  因为你被禁止入内了
And you'll never know, because you're banned!
等等
Hey, wait a minute.
这会儿无花果酱店有人吗
Is anyone even watching Fig Jam right now?
雷  搞不好正被人洗劫一空哦
Ray, people are probably looting it.
一大群嬉皮士正把乳酪
A bunch of hippies stuffing truffled cheese
往他们的琴盒里塞
in their banjo cases.
有人吗
Hello?
Hello...?
我把钱放柜台了哦
I'm just gonna leave money on the counter.
很喜欢你的店哦
Love your store.
天呐  我的店  我的店
Oh, my God. Fig Jam! Fig Jam!
刚才三轮骑的不错嘛  菜鸟
That was some mean pedi-cabbing out there, rookie.
你长着一双耗子腿  却有一颗狮子心
You got the legs of a mouse but the heart of a lion.
我叔叔家就有狮子的心脏
My uncle's got the heart of a lion.
他从泰国买回来的
He got it in Thailand.
-泰国么  -是的
- Thailand, huh? - Yeah.
泰国有好的领带吗
They got nice ties in Thailand?
我真喜欢你  曼尼
I love you, Manny.
就快到了
I'm almost there.
热巧克力洗车服务
Hot Fudge Car Wash.
Hot Fudge Car Wash?!
不
No...!
吉恩来了  鲍勃  吉恩来了
Oh, it's Gene. Bob, it's Gene.
-老爸  -吉恩
- Dad...! - Gene!
对不起我今天搞砸了
I-I'm sorry I screwed up today!
我
I...
对不起我总是把事情搞砸
I'm sorry I screw up all the time!
不  吉恩  你没搞砸
No, Gene, you didn't screw up.
都怪我太信任你
I screwed up by trusting you.
等下  说漏嘴了
Wait, that came out wrong.
我没听懂  你这是想让我好受点吗
I'm confused, are you trying to make me feel better?
是的
Yes, I am.
在把黑蒜交给你之前
Before I give you the black garlic,
我还有一句话想说
I just want to say one more thing.
只剩45秒了  吉恩
There's only 45 seconds left, Gene, so...
我一直很尊敬你
I've always admired you.
快把蒜给我  吉恩
Just give me the garlic, Gene!
我们一会儿再谈
We'll talk later!
-好吧  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
抱歉打断你了
Sorry I snapped.
快  鲍鲍
Come on, Bobby.
手套拿回来了  该去战胜阿波罗了
You got your gloves, now time to beat Apollo.
艾黛丽安
Adrian...!
不  别那样  好好喊
No, not like that. Say it right.
什么  我就是好好喊的
What?! I'm saying it right.
艾黛..  没时间了  琳
Adri... I don't have time, Lin.
最后十秒钟
Ten seconds left.
看来某位大厨搞不定了
Some cooks look like they might not make it.
-说的就是鲍勃  -十
- I'm talking about Bob. - Ten.
九  八
Nine. Eight.
七
Seven.
-我这边都准备好了  快点  -六
- I got everything ready. Here we go. - Six.
五
Five.
四
Four.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
时间到  全都住手  大厨们
Time's up. Hand off your meat, chefs.
我们完成了
We finished!
我们做成汉堡了
We finished the burgers!
为鲍勃欢呼  他差点就
Hooray for Bob. He managed to somehow do
搞砸他每天都在干的事儿
what he does every day for a living.
真是不容易
What a champion.
这才是我的鲍鲍
That's my Bobby!
大厨们
Chefs.
请
Pre...
把你们的汉堡呈给评委们
sent your burgers to the judges.
看来评委选择
Looks like the judges
先品尝吉米・派丝多的汉堡
are tasting Jimmy Pesto's burger first.
我们来看看...
Let's see how he...
他们吐出来了
they are spitting it out.
没关系
Oh, it's cool.
我店周二晚披萨加量不加价
Hey, two-for-one pizza night Wednesdays,
周三卡拉OK狂欢
karaoke Tuesdays,
周四八卦日
trivia Thursdays. We never card.
欢迎各位光临
Come on down!
谢谢  吉米
Thank you, Jimmy.
评委都吐出来了  可不是啥好征兆
Spitting it out... bad sign.
我看你可以回家了
You can probably go.
走吧  崔佛
Come on, Trev.
抱歉我刚刚对你太苛刻了
Hey, I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
情势那会儿有些白热化
Things got a little heated.
还不仅是加热灯的关系
And not just 'cause of your heat lamp.
你刚说"苛刻"
You said "Hard."
是的  击掌
I did. Up top.
好了  现在要尝鲍勃的弱智汉堡了
All right, now they're tasting Bob's idiot burger.
多半又得吐一次了
Get ready for another spit-out.
这真是
This is...
太棒了
fantastic.
肉调味得恰到好处
The meat is seasoned perfectly,
而且这黑蒜简直...
and this black garlic is...
这口感太高级了
This has exquisite mouth feel.
鲍鲍  他们喜欢诶
Bobby, they loved it!
最后那人略变态  但他也喜欢诶
That one's creepy, but he loved it.
天呐  我们这是赢了吗
Oh, my God. Did we just win?
虽然他们还没尝斯基普的汉堡
I mean, they still haven't had Skip's burger, but...
现在是最后一位
And now the last,
也很可能是最优秀的参赛选手
but most likely the best,
来自肉桂种马餐厅的斯基普・马瑞琪
from the Cinnamon Stallion, Skip Marooch.
这真是
This is...
太赞了
amazing.
这酸辣酱太...
This chutney is absolutely,
口感独一无二
Exceptional mouth feel.
感觉没差啊
It might be a little closer than I thought.
可以  可以  鲍勃
Okay. Okay, Bob.
你得到的是"棒极了"和"哇"
You got a "Fantastic" And an "Ooh,"
而他得到的是"太赞了"和一声诡异的呻吟
but he got an "Amazing" and a really weird moan.
而最后那人表示两个口感都不错
And he liked both your mouth feels.
我看不相上下啊
I'd say it's a tight race.
现在评委将会商议最后结果
And now the judges will deliberate.
请放评委讨论音乐
Cue deliberating music, please.
我尽全力了
You know what? I did my best,
我靠自己的实力和斯基普比的
I held my own with Skip,
无论结果怎样
and no matter what happens, Lin,
我都心满意足
I feel pretty good.
获胜者是斯基普・马瑞琪
And the winner is Skip Marooch!
获胜者  斯基普・马瑞琪
天呐  我好难过
Oh, my God, I feel bad.
该死  太垃圾了
Ah, damn it! Piece of garbage!
我们怎么可能输
How could we lose?!
-是在开我玩笑吗  -好了  好了
- Are you kidding me?! - Okay. Okay.
是汉堡的形状呢  我赢啦
it's shaped like a burger! I get it!
我好激动
I'm so excited!
斯基普・马瑞琪  型男大厨
Skip Marooch, handsomest chef.
本人呢
What about me?
一级棒主持人
Great MC.
我要去
Gonna go have
来盘虾  一杯酒
a plate of shrimp, a 20-ounce beer
再到我的朋友
and a massage,
女按摩师菡可那儿  去按个摩
from my friend, Hank the masseuse...
老天爷
Oh, my God.
真遗憾你输了  老爸
Sorry you lost, Dad.
也许我早点把黑蒜送到
Maybe if I'd gotten you the black garlic sooner,
你就能赢了
you would have won.
不不  我们已经尽全力了
No, no. We made the best burger we could,
但还是输了  没事的
but we lost, and that's okay.
我不需要什么借口
I don't need an excuse.
他不过是比你更有魅力  更惹人爱罢了
I guess Skip was just more charismatic and likeable, Dad.
你说得对
That's right.
不  我不需要借口
No! I don't need an excuse.
无论如何  我要说声抱歉
Either way, I'm sorry.
听我说  吉恩
Listen, Gene.
你虽然常常分心
You may get distracted from time to time,
但我爱的就是这样的你
but I love you and I love who you are.
重要的是...吉恩
And what matters most is... Gene?
吉恩  你在听吗
Gene, are you listening?!
在听  在听  我爱你
I am. I am. I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
不过那些人
But what are those people
在餐厅前排队做什么
doing waiting in front of the restaurant?
我们的餐厅可从来不需要排队啊
People don't wait for our restaurant.
大概他们都等着用洗手间吧
Maybe they all need to use the bathroom.
散了散了
Hey, get out of here!
去草丛尿去  大家不都是这样嘛
Go pee in the bushes like normal people.
你们营业吗
Are you guys open?
我们想尝尝黑蒜汉堡
We want to try that black garlic burger.
能让我也尝一尝黑蒜汉堡吗
Can I have a black garlic burger, too?
-斯基普  你怎么来了  -是我
- Skip? What the hell? - Yeah.
你想吃我的汉堡
You want to try my burger?
对  我闻到味儿了  现在想尝尝味儿
Yeah, I smelt it, and now I want you to dealt it.
用嘴
Into my mouth.
快进来吧  稍等个几分钟
Come on in. W-We just need a few minutes
让我们把烤架点上
to get the grill going.
吉恩  能帮忙去开烤架吗
Gene, you want to go start the grill?
不要  我的休假从现在开始
Nope. My day off starts now.
接下来的24小时我都要
And I will be spending the next 24 hours
在热巧克力洗车服务中心度过  回见
at the Hot Fudge Car Wash. Bye-bye.
吉恩
Gene!
-啥  -你刚是说热巧克力洗车吗
- Yeah? - Did you just say "Hot Fudge Car Wash"?
-对  -我也要从现在开始休假  回见
- I did. - My day off starts now, too. Bye-bye.
等等  还有那么多客人呢
Wait. We have customers.
抱歉  老爸  我得去看看
Sorry, Dad. I have to go see
热巧克力洗车是咋洗的
a car wash about a fudge.
给妈妈打包一桶回来
Get Mommy a to-go bucket.
*热巧克力洗车*
*Hot Fudge Car Wash*
*热  热  热  热巧克力*
*Hot, hot, hot, hot fudge*
*热巧克力洗车*
*Hot Fudge Car Wash*
*热  热  热  热巧克力*
*Hot, hot, hot, hot fudge*
*热巧克力洗车*
*Hot Fudge Car Wash*
*热  热  热  热巧克力*
*Hot, hot, hot, hot fudge*
*热巧克力洗车*
*Hot Fudge Car Wash*
*热巧克力*
*Ooh... hot fudge!*